



Cesar Napoles

Nationality: Cuban Date of birth: 24/11/1990

S Skype: live:juliocesarnapolespuente in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jcnapoles

Website: <u>cesarnapoles.com</u>

ABOUT ME

I offer more than 10 years of experience as Computer Engineer, highly prepared as a software developer, in analysis and technical consultancy.

I am used to solving problems and unforeseen events autonomously, and with the ability to successfully combine different tasks. I am characterized by responsibility, proactivity, organization, and commitment to work.

Ease of communication and great ability to work as a team. High willingness for professional improvement according to the work environment, the tools, and technologies used.bout yourself

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Amaris Consulting [06/05/2021 - Current]

City: Barelona | Country: Spain

- Analysis, design and development of applications.
- Technical and functional consulting.
- · Development, maintenance and migration of legacy applications, JAVA, Angular, Spring, React.
- · Development and integration of APIs

Software Engineer

Isern Patentes y Marcas [29/07/2018 - 01/05/2021]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain

- Analysis, design and development of applications.
- Web developer
- Database developer, maintenance, user support.

Completed tasks:

- IsernTools, web management tool.
- Similar Files Detector v1.0. Artificial Intelligence Project in collaboration with UPC (Polytechnic University of Catalonia)
- Import of Bulletins. Automated program for downloading and uploading Bulletins in Database
- ISERN Images. Image processing program for Isern users.
- Client with an interface to consume web services published by the OEPM (www.oepm.es)

Technical environment: Java EE, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 Soapui, JUnit, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Boot, jQuery, Maven, Spring Roo, BIRT (Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools), Soap / Rest (JSON, XML), Bootstrap, JPA-Hibernate, Intersystems Cache, MySQL, SVN, GIT, Apache CXF.

Full Stack Developer

Indra [27/07/2016 - 05/06/2018]

City: Montevideo | Country: Uruguay

- Analysis, design, and development of business applications.
- Technical and functional consulting.

Completed tasks:

- InGRID MDM project for the management and estimation of electrical measurements with implementation in Uruguay.
- Maintaining the quality of the code, automating tasks, and optimizing processes seeking a better user experience.
- API Rest Inventory for exchange with external tools of the client company.

Technical environment: BigData Cloudera (Hadoop, MapReduce, HBase), Spring, JPA, Hibernate, Quartz, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Boot, jQuery, Maven, Spring Roo, BIRT (Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools), Soap / Rest (JSON, XML), Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Apache CXF.

QA tester

Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas [03/09/2014 – 15/07/2016]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba

• Quality Management Tester of projects developed at the University of Computer Science

Completed tasks:

- Functional Tests, Design and Execution of Test Cases
- Test Plan Design
- Automated Tests

Technical environment: Selenium, JMeter, JUnit, Linux, Microsoft Office, Open Office, Redmine.

Software developer

Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas [03/09/2012 - 15/08/2014]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba

Web developer

Completed tasks:

• Development of tools to manage components (services and dependencies) in XAUCE (Business framework).

Technical environment: PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ExtJS

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Computer Science Engineer, Informatics Engineering

Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas [08/2009 - 07/2014]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba | Website: www.uci.cu

Master's degree in Big Data with Phyton

Escuela Superior de Informatica CIPSA [15/06/2019 - 15/06/2020]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: cipsa.net

Master's degree in Java EE

Escuela Superior de Informatica CIPSA [15/06/2018 - 10/06/2019]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: cipsa.net

Cloud administration (Azure, AWS, Google Cloud)

Amaris Consulting [10/11/2022 - 10/06/2023]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: amaris.com

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Spanish

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming languages

Java / JavaScript / HTML5 / CSS3 / PHP / JPA / Typescript / hibernate ORM / SQL

Frameworks

Bootstrap / Spring / Angular / React / Maven / JavaScript - JQuery / Spring Quartz / HADOOP

Version Control

Git / SVN / LiquiBase

Testing

Cypress / JUNIT / Apache Jmeter / SoapUi / Selenium / Jest / cURL / Postman

Managment

JIRA / Redmine / Trello

CI/CD

Docker / Jenkins / GitHub, GitHub Actions

Cloud Platforms

AWS / Heroku / Azure

Agile

Scrum

IDES

Spring Tool Suite (STS) / VSCode, Visual Studio / JetBrains Intellij Idea / Visual Paradigm / BIRT report designer / Eclipse / NetBeans / DBeaver